<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>MetaPipe - free</title><link href="https://www.metapipe.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="localhost:8000/feeds/free.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://www.metapipe.com/</id><updated>2017-04-07T16:30:00-06:00</updated><entry><title>Creating Panoramas for CG</title><link href="https://www.metapipe.com/blog/posts/2017/04/07/creating-panos-for-cg/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-04-07T16:30:00-06:00</published><updated>2017-04-07T16:30:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Aaron Estrada</name></author><id>tag:www.metapipe.com,2017-04-07:/blog/posts/2017/04/07/creating-panos-for-cg/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Free Nuke tutorials on how to create Tile Worlds and use Panoramas in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;CG&lt;/span&gt;. &lt;span class="caps"&gt;PLUS&lt;/span&gt;, advanced green screen matte extraction&amp;nbsp;techniques.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tile Worlds, Camera Projection and Image Based Lighting all have one thing in
common: They use photographic elements as their main source inputs. While I tend
to say this about nearly every &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VFX&lt;/span&gt; technique (I love them all!), the above are
among my favorites. There is nothing more photo-realistic than a photograph or
live action plate so it’s the best source material one can hope for! More
excitingly, once you understand how they work, the techniques allow you to mix
and match and move back and forth between &lt;span class="caps"&gt;C.G.&lt;/span&gt; and reality as you see&amp;nbsp;fit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Tileworld How-To Illustration" src="/static/img/blog/tile_world_figure_s.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After releasing the &lt;a href="/offers/railyard-hdri/"&gt;free &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HDRI&lt;/span&gt; panoramas&lt;/a&gt;, we received some questions as to just
how they might be useful for &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VFX&lt;/span&gt;.  It’s easy to say “Virtual Set” and &amp;#8220;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;IBL&lt;/span&gt;&amp;#8221; but
not so easy to visualize if you aren’t familiar with the techniques involved.
To help everyone build some new skills, we decided to give away some lessons on
Tile Worlds and panoramas so people can try their hand at using the panoramas we
gave away last week. It doesn&amp;#8217;t cover Image Based Lighting but it should give
you a sense of how you can use panoramas for virtual&amp;nbsp;sets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned, along with matte paintings, camera projection, and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;IBL&lt;/span&gt; these are
some of my favorite &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VFX&lt;/span&gt; techniques. It’s possible to get very impressive results
without a huge amount of effort. I’m excited to be able to share these
techniques with you and hope they help you create some amazing stuff. In fact,
everyone here would love to see what you come up with. If you make something
cool using these techniques, please post them on your video sharing site of
choice and share the link with us:
&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/fullmetapipe"&gt;@FullMetaPipe&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter or
&lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/metapipe"&gt;@MetaPipe&lt;/a&gt; on&amp;nbsp;Facebook.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Pano/Tileworld WIP" src="/static/img/blog/tile_world_figure2_s.jpg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can use the non-commercial version of Nuke or use Blackmagic Design&amp;#8217;s Fusion
for your experiments. The techniques work in either. They are probably adaptable
to After Effects, though I’m not familiar enough with the 3D system in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;AE&lt;/span&gt; to say
for certain. The Tile World technique will also work in any 3D package that has
a camera with a physically accurate aperture gate and lens system so you can
even do it right in your favorite 3D system if you&amp;nbsp;like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the links to the lessons (over two and a half hours of free training).
You need to register but the lessons are free: &lt;a href="http://courses.learnvfx.com/courses/nk101?coupon=metapipe_blog_pano_promo"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NK101&lt;/span&gt; Lesson 7: Intro to Nuke’s
3D system and Tile
Worlds&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a href="http://courses.learnvfx.com/courses/nk201?coupon=metapipe_blog_pano_promo"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NK201&lt;/span&gt; Lesson 3: Mixing Scale and Deep&amp;nbsp;Compositing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you like what you see, here is a coupon code for 80% off anything at
LearnVFX:&amp;nbsp;metapipe_blog_pano_promo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I already applied it to the links above for you. You can also manually enter it
at&amp;nbsp;checkout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The coupon makes the &lt;a href="http://courses.learnvfx.com/bundles/nk101-and-nk201?coupon=metapipe_blog_pano_promo"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;NK101&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NK201&lt;/span&gt;
bundle&lt;/a&gt;
just $49.60 (normally&amp;nbsp;$248.00)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The free lessons are free forever but the coupon for 80% off lifetime access
expires April 30th&amp;nbsp;2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enjoy the free&amp;nbsp;lessons!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="free"></category></entry><entry><title>LearnVFX Acquisition</title><link href="https://www.metapipe.com/blog/posts/2017/03/22/learnvfx-acquired-by-fullmeta/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-03-22T12:30:54-07:00</published><updated>2017-03-22T12:30:54-07:00</updated><author><name>Aaron Estrada</name></author><id>tag:www.metapipe.com,2017-03-22:/blog/posts/2017/03/22/learnvfx-acquired-by-fullmeta/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;LearnVFX.com has been acquired by FullMeta Corp. (Creators of MetaPipe.com). To celebrate, we are giving away a free book, Pipeline&amp;nbsp;101&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;FullMeta Corp., the creators of MetaPipe.com have acquired
LearnVFX.com, my former training company.  LearnVFX will become our
portal for providing training and cool content for the &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VFX&lt;/span&gt; and
animation&amp;nbsp;community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To celebrate we’ve decided to give away my latest creation, Pipeline
101, a free crash course book on &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VFX&lt;/span&gt; and animation pipelines. Feel
free to share the link below. Pipeline 101 is for anyone interested in
how &lt;span class="caps"&gt;C.G.&lt;/span&gt; animation and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VFX&lt;/span&gt; studios work under the hood. Did I mention
it’s&amp;nbsp;free?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Grab your free copy here: &lt;a href="/offers/pipeline101/?utm_source=metapipe.com&amp;amp;utm_medium=blog-post&amp;amp;utm_campaign=pipeline101"&gt;Pipeline&amp;nbsp;101&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="free"></category></entry></feed>