<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>MetaPipe - sxsw</title><link href="https://www.metapipe.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="localhost:8000/feeds/sxsw.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://www.metapipe.com/</id><updated>2017-03-17T07:30:00-06:00</updated><entry><title>SXSW 2017</title><link href="https://www.metapipe.com/blog/posts/2017/03/17/sxsw-2017/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-03-17T07:30:00-06:00</published><updated>2017-03-17T07:30:00-06:00</updated><author><name>Aaron Estrada</name></author><id>tag:www.metapipe.com,2017-03-17:/blog/posts/2017/03/17/sxsw-2017/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Aaron attended sxsw 2017 and it was incredibly inspirational. There’s never been a better time to be a filmmaker. These days, the only constraint in what you can do is your imagination and&amp;nbsp;skill.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you’ve been watching the
&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/FullMetaPipe"&gt;MetaPipe Twitter feed&lt;/a&gt; you know I
was at South by Southwest this&amp;nbsp;week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was my first time at sxsw and I have to say I was blown away by the
energy and how amazing all the people are. It was incredibly
inspirational. There is a vibe that can only be described as joy. I’m
guessing it stems from the roots of sxsw as a mostly cultural event. A
huge percentage of the people who attend are there to see new movies
and hear new music. They are there to have fun and discover new&amp;nbsp;things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went on an Interactive badge and my primary goal was to network. The
fact everyone was in such a great mood made breaking the ice with
complete strangers easy. I met many fantastic people and had many
great conversations about filmmaking and &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VR&lt;/span&gt;. I also managed to attend
some great presentations and&amp;nbsp;speeches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I had to say what the big takeaway was from my personal perspective
it would be: &lt;strong&gt;There’s never been a better time to be a&amp;nbsp;filmmaker.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gareth Edwards mentioned it in his
&lt;a href="https://www.sxsw.com/film/2017/gareth-edwards-film-keynote-speaker-2017-sxsw-conference-video/"&gt;Key Note&lt;/a&gt;
and Casey Neistat mentioned it in
&lt;a href="https://youtu.be/rAZyGj83gJo?t=19m9s"&gt;his speech&lt;/a&gt; as well. This is
something I’ve believed since the first &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DV&lt;/span&gt; cameras hit the market in
1995 and even more so since powerful smartphones with &lt;span class="caps"&gt;HD&lt;/span&gt; cameras
became the norm. Camera technology has hit a point where even the most
modest cameras are superior to 16mm film and in some cases even older
35mm film&amp;nbsp;stocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are no excuses left except for the fear of&amp;nbsp;failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that in our hearts, many &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VFX&lt;/span&gt; artists are frustrated filmmakers
the way Gareth Edwards described himself when he was only doing &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VFX&lt;/span&gt;
work. I know I certainly was! When I was at Dreawworks Animation, we
even had a little group called Film Club where we got together to make
48 hour films.  Some of the people in the group had &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VFX&lt;/span&gt; backgrounds,
others had only ever done animation but the common thread was we
wanted more experience with what Gareth described in his talk as “real
time rendering” through the camera. It’s a great way to practice
composition and film language &lt;span class="caps"&gt;QUICKLY&lt;/span&gt; as compared to using computer
graphics. If you haven’t experimented with cameras as a way to
practice your composition and blocking skills, I highly reccomended
it! Photography is also a great way to drive your &lt;span class="caps"&gt;VFX&lt;/span&gt; work, for
example with techniques like photogrammetry, projection mapping and
tile&amp;nbsp;worlds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These days, the only constraints in what you can achieve really are
your own imagination and skill. With the cloud, even the constraints
of finite compute resources have been erased. You can think bigger.
Finding collaborators can still be a challenge but we hope to help
with that.  We want to empower people with MetaPipe in every way
possible. We started the company to help remove the technical barriers
holding back artists but as a natural benefit of working in the cloud,
remote collaboration becomes a first class feature. If you have a
dream you want to bring to fruition, contact us. We want to hear from&amp;nbsp;you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="sxsw"></category><category term="conference"></category><category term="inspiration"></category></entry></feed>